<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jack&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jack&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Journalism with D3.js - The 2019 UK General Election</title>
      <link>/post/data-journalism-with-d3-js-the-2019-uk-general-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-journalism-with-d3-js-the-2019-uk-general-election/</guid>
      <description>The 2019 United Kingdom general election was held on Thursday 12 December 2019. The Conservative Party, having failed to obtain a majority in the 2017 general election, had faced a prolonged parliamentary deadlock over Brexit while it governed in minority with the support of the Democratic Unionist Party (DUP) which had forced the resignation of the previous Prime Minister Theresa May. As a result, Boris Johnson called for an early election to take place in December, which was eventually passed into law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future is Electric - MSc Dissertation - Executive Summary</title>
      <link>/post/msc-dissertation-executive-summary-electric-vehicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/msc-dissertation-executive-summary-electric-vehicles/</guid>
      <description>During my time at the Centre of Urban Science and Progress at King&amp;rsquo;s College London, I had the opportunity to collaborate with Westminster City Council to evaluate the current state of electric vehicle charge point infrastructure and advise its most efficient distribution. This project used electric vehicle charging transaction data from 2018-2019 and included data mining, spatial statistics and network analysis techniques in order to address the problems they were facing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Algorithms - DBSCAN/OPTICS</title>
      <link>/post/visualising-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualising-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>DBSCAN/OPTICS Density-based spatial clustering of applications with noise (DBSCAN)1 is an incredibly powerful and popular data mining technique for unsupervised learning. It is able to detect clusters based on their density without having to specify the number of clusters we want. The main drawbacks, however, are its highly sensitive dependancy on the initial parameters (𝜀 and MinPts) as well as its inability to detect clusters of varying density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will the Real Smart City Please Stand Up?</title>
      <link>/post/will-the-real-smart-city-please-stand-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/will-the-real-smart-city-please-stand-up/</guid>
      <description>The 2018 revision of the United Nations World Urbanisation Prospects state that 55% of the world population is currently living in urban areas1. This figure is set to increase to 68% by 2050. Now, North America stands as the most urbanised, with 82% of its population living in urban areas. The definition of “smart city” has not been explicitly articulated in the literature with varying suggestions under differing prefixes such as “intelligent”2 and “digital”3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loom Art - Image Processing - OpenCV/D3.js</title>
      <link>/post/loom-art-opencv-d3-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/loom-art-opencv-d3-js/</guid>
      <description>The inspiration for this project came from two places. The first after being unable to solve this puzzle in the New Scientist (which can be compared to drawing lines through the pixels of an image). The second was seeing other examples of this type of art style, for example this piece by Petros Vrellis, and wondering what method was used to determine the order in which the threads should be placed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maps, Maps, Maps! Learning ArcGIS</title>
      <link>/post/maps-maps-maps-learning-arcgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/maps-maps-maps-learning-arcgis/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to answer the question: Where are the best places to live in London? It does this by composite, weight indexing of a number of different variables. Six variables were chosen based on attributes one might look for when buying a property. These six variables are as follows:
 House Prices
 Air Pollution
 Crime Density
 Population Density
 Hospital Accessibility
 Transport Accessibility  Data for all six attributes were collected and visualised in ArcGIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blogdown!</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>…Hello Netlify, Hello Hugo, Hello Tanka, Hello World! This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>